# NICHOLAS DeCHANT

Bellevue, Washington · (425) 922-1585 · dchant@uw.edu · in/NicholasDeChant · nickdec.github.io

A skilled Data Analyst with solid analytical experience and 5+ years working as a customer service and hospitality professional. Currently a Loyalty Analyst for PACCAR Parts division. Areas of expertise include handling multiple projects and priorities, interpreting data, and reporting findings with Tableau to present insight for decision making.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Sr. Retail Promotions Analyst, PACCAR Parts

March 2021 - Current

- Develop advanced data analytics tools for reporting customer and dealer loyalty metrics.
  - Query Snowflake database to gather loyalty data and develop dashboards for use by Paccar on Tableau Server.
  - Designed popular YTD/PYTD performance Tableau dashboards for Membership Signups and Redemption Summaries, as well as over 110+ workbooks, 65 projects+ on Tableau Server applying advanced concepts: context filtering/Level of Detail calculations to create accurate and dependable reporting for company use.
- Provide expertise on the loyalty program and present information to internal and external clients.
  - Conduct monthly WebEx seminars for Loyalty program updates to Kenworth and Peterbilt dealers.
  - Provide training for Parts and Sales Managers on how to utilize the loyalty program and increase sales.
- Analyze and solve technical business and customer issues within the loyalty system.
  - Assist dealers with Loyalty issues, coupon errors on business systems/eCommerce, and loyalty reporting.
  - Solve and troubleshoot issues across multiple technologies and systems (eCommerce, DBS, Loyalty app).
- Coordinate and assist integrating dealer business systems for embedded customer loyalty.
  - Consult with notably KARMAK, CDK, and DSI to ensure Loyalty capability and support customer inquiries.

#### **Guest Services Associate, Hilton**

June 2017 – April 2020

- Create reservations, check-in guests, and ensure all guests requests are achieved accordingly.
- Arrange transportation services for guests to local businesses, restaurants, and airport.
- Maintain top tier customer service and a high level of professionalism in a team environment.

#### Support Manager, DCS Inc.

March 2015 - January 2017

- Assisted with Close-Range Photogrammetry workshops, provided by DCS at customer's facilities.
- Trained clients with photogrammetric software and provided maintenance services.
- Provided software technical support to customers, and webmaster for the company website.

#### TECHNOLOGIES and SKILLS

Programming: SQL, Java, Python, R, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSON

Software: Tableau, Tableau Server, Tableau Prep, Alteryx, Snowflake, SQL Server, MongoDB Compass, Rstudio

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Alteryx Designer Core | Alteryx | September 2020

Tableau Desktop Specialist | Tableau Software | February 2020

Exam 98-364: Database Fundamentals | Microsoft | July 2019

#### **EDUCATION**

BA, Mathematics

Fall 2011 - Spring 2015

University of Washington

**Certificate of Business Intelligence** 

Bellevue College

Fall 2018 - Spring 2020